《神奇四侠2：银影侠现身》
(日本 骏河湾)
阿俊,你每天都鱼腥味好厉害啊
- 啊?你不也是么? - 这才叫做男子汉嘛
- 阿俊 - 怎么了
这是怎么回事?
快上船
这究竟是怎么回事啊
(埃及 吉萨金字塔)
(加利福尼亚 洛杉矶)
Last night, the FAA was forced to ground all aircraft, leaving thousands stranded...
昨晚,神秘的大面积停电席卷美国西部
...when electronic failures and mysterious power outages...
联邦航空局被迫暂停所有航班 致使成千上万的旅客滞留
...crippled the western United States. But the big story today...
但是今天最大的新闻是倍受瞩目的…
...the much-anticipated wedding of fantastic couple...
神奇情侣里德·理查斯和苏·史东的婚礼
...Reed Richards and Susan Storm will take place this Saturday.
将在本周六举行
Unbelievable. Bizarre anomalies...
难以置信,全球各地持续发生异常的…
...are occurring all over the world, defying every law of physics...
违背破物理定律的古怪现象
...and all the media care about is what china pattern we picked.
而所有的媒体却只关心 我们会选哪种样式的瓷器
What did you pick? The blue ones with them little flowers? I like them.
你选了哪一种?蓝底碎花的? 我真的很喜欢那个
Excuse me, would you mind?
请原谅,你介不介意跟我合张影?
- It's happening again, isn't it? - Yeah, sure.
- 又来了,是不是? - 好的,当然
No. We're not postponing anything, not this time.
不,我们什么都不会推迟 这次绝不推迟
This will be the wedding you dreamed of. I won't let anything get in the way.
这将会是你梦想中的婚礼 我不会让任何事情破坏它
Not even the mysterious transformation of matter at the subatomic level.
就算是那些神秘的 亚原子连锁转化也不行
That's the most romantic thing you've ever said to me.
这是你对我说过的最浪漫的话了
Which is really pathetic, when you think about it.
仔细想想,却又觉得有些悲凉
Dr. Richards, I'm very sorry, but we're overbooked.
理查斯博士,非常抱歉 但机位已经订光了
- We do have seats available in coach. - Okay, here we go.
- 不过还有一些经济舱的座位 - 照了啊
- Smile! - Awesome!
- 笑一笑 - 太棒啦
Look, Mom!
看啊,妈妈
- Let me get one more. - That should be fine.
- 好极了,我们再来一张 - 没问题
That's my seat.
呃,那是我的位子
Sorry.
对不起
Excuse me.
劳驾
What if we get an endorsement from an airline? Get us a private jet?
你们觉得我们帮航空公司代言如何? 说不定可以给我们一台私人飞机喔
I think we have enough endorsement deals.
我想我们已经代言够多的东西了
That's funny. Seriously, Reed, it could help subsidize your little inventions.
真好笑,说真的,里德,这些资金 对你发明的那些小东西有帮助呢
- No, thanks. - Excuse me.
- 不,谢谢了 - 劳驾
- Consider it. Talk to you later. - Where are you going?
- 考虑一下吧,回头再谈 - 强尼,你要去哪?
I don't fly coach.
我不坐经济舱
I hope it rains.
真希望老天下场雨
The snowfall came with no warning...
大雪突降,没有预兆 气温也没有变化
...and covered the pyramids in 2 inches of snow.
金字塔被两英尺厚的大雪覆盖
In Japan, some suggest the solidification of the bay...
而在日本,有人认为海湾被冰冻
...was due to underwater volcanic activity...
是由于海底火山活动引起的
...though no such activity has been reported in the area.
但是从未有报道说在 该地区有这类地质活动
Scientists have ruled out global warming...
科学家们已经排除了全球气候变暖
...as the cause of the climatic events being reported around the globe.
是全球各地产生极端气候现象的原因
With scientists unable to explain the events...
科学家们无法解释这些奇异的现象
...some are wondering if the hand of God is at work.
有人开始怀疑是否是上帝旨意
In other news, Reed Richards and Susan Storm's wedding...
现在播送其它新闻 里德·理查斯和苏珊·史东的婚礼
...has Manhattan all abuzz.
轰动了曼哈顿
The guest list includes many of New York's power elite.
宾客名单中包括了诸多 纽约政商界的精英
Hey, honey.
嗨,亲爱的
The city's charging us for three squad cars they say we destroyed...
市政府责令我们赔偿3辆警察巡逻车 他们说是我们破坏的
...during that armored-car robbery. I only remember two cars getting thrown.
就是在那次的抢劫运钞车事件 但我记得只掀翻了两辆警车
Reed.
里德
All right. I'm putting it away.
好的,好的,好的 我放到一边去
You were saying?
你刚刚说什么来着?
I have a fitting in half an hour. The musicians after that.
我半个小时后要去试婚纱 然后选乐师
I haven't picked out the place settings or the flowers. There's too much to do.
我还没选好场景布置还有鲜花 需要做的事情太多了
Don't worry about it. Between the two of us, we'll get it all done.
嘿,不要担心,我肯定 我们两会一起把一切搞定的
And what were you doing when I walked in?
那么我进来的时候你在干什么呢?
- Inputting my to-do list. - Really?
- 我正在输入我的任务清单 - 真的?
- Scout's honor. - Hey, guys.
- 以童子军的荣誉担保 - 嘿,伙计们
New uniforms showed up. What do you think?
新制服出炉了,你们觉得怎么样
I think there's no way we're wearing that.
我想我们决不会穿的,强尼
What do you have against capitalism?
你对资本主义有看法啊?!
What's this?
这是什么?
- Just a little hobby of mine. - Yeah?
- 只是我个人爱好 - 是吗?
Would it make a good toy, or is it something science-y?
究竟是个玩具啊 还是搞科学研究用的
A little of both.
都有点
I'm both impressed and disgusted at that.
你知道,我对你这种 操作方式深恶痛绝
Yeah. Sue says I'm addicted to it.
是啊,苏说我对这个上瘾了
I wonder why she'd say that.
我不明白她为什么会那样说
Hey, Johnny.
嘿,强尼
Keep it quiet, but I've cross-referenced and analyzed the global disturbances.
小声点,但是我交叉分析了 全球紊乱现象
They're caused by cosmic radiation, not unlike the kind which gave us our powers.
它们是由宇宙辐射引起的 但又不像是给我们提供能量的那种
Wow, that's really boring.
哇,那可真够无聊的
Listen, I have a very important wedding issue we need to talk about.
听着,我有件非常重要的 婚礼事宜要和你商量
Yeah, of course.
是的,当然
Your bachelor party.
你的告别单身派对
No. Seriously, Johnny.
不要,说真的,强尼
John. Focus-testing showed Johnny skewed a little young.
强尼,民意测验表明强尼 心理年龄比其外表年轻
Seriously, Johnny, no bachelor party. It's just not my kind of thing.
说真的,强尼,不要办告别单身派对 那不是我的行事风格
Then do it for Ben. It means a lot to the big guy. You'll break his heart.
那就为了本,这对那个大家伙很重要 不然会伤透他的心的
He does have some sort of rocklike heart.
他的心可是石头做的,不是吗
I have too much to do before the wedding.
婚礼前我有很多事情要做
I think Sue might have a problem with it.
我想苏也会有意见的
You know what Sue would have a problem with?
你知道我觉得苏会对什么有意见吗?
If somebody told her you were investigating...
如果有人告诉她 你实际上正在调查…
...global disturbances and cosmic radiation...
全球紊乱现象和宇宙辐射…
...instead of focusing on the wedding, like you promised.
而不是像你保证的那样,专注于婚礼
- A bachelor party could be fun. - Yes!
- 告别单身派对应该很有趣 - 太好了
But no exotic dancers.
但不要脱衣舞娘
(拉脱维亚 哈森斯丹特)
- This is it? - I don't know anybody here.
- 就是这儿了? - 这里没一个我认识的
I would have invited your friends, but you don't have any.
是啊,我本来应该邀请一些你的朋友的 但是你没有朋友
Hey!
嘿
Johnny, we had a deal.
强尼,我们说好了的
They're not exotic dancers.
她们不是脱衣舞娘
They're just hot.
她们只是辣妹
You're Mr. Fantastic, aren't you? That's so awesome.
你就是神奇先生,对吧?你太棒了
Wow, you're really cute.
哇,你真的很帅呦
I'll need a pitcher with the biggest handle you've got.
来杯喝的,用你们这里最大的杯子
No problem.
好的
Good evening, and welcome to the Baxter...
晚上好,欢迎来到巴克斯特大厦…
Could I help you? No, you can't use that elev...
有什么能为你们效劳的 你们不能乘那电梯
Ms. Storm will be with your shortly.
史东女士马上就到
Hello?
你们好?
Thanks, Roberta.
谢谢,罗贝塔
May I help you?
有何贵干?
- We're here to see Dr. Richards. - He's not here. Can I help you?
- 我们要见理查斯博士 - 很抱歉,他现在不在,我能帮忙吗?
Yes. You can take me to see Dr. Richards.
是的,你可以带我们去见理查斯博士
Okay.
好吧
Sorry.
对不起
When the universe began, it was no bigger than a marble. Then, bang!
当整个宇宙起源的时候 还没一块小石子大,然后"碰"的一声
It exploded. And in a trillionth of a second...
它爆炸了,在万亿分之一秒的时间内…
...it expanded exponentially into what became the universe we know.
它就扩张成了我们所知道的 宇宙现在的样子
Wow, you're really smart.
哇,你真的好聪明啊
Thanks, Candy. That means a lot to me.
谢谢,坎蒂,你这么说我很感动
I love this song. Wanna dance?
我爱死这首歌了,你想跳舞吗?
- No, I don't. - Yes, you do.
- 不,我不想 - 不,你想跳的,来吧
- Honestly. - Come on, you'll be great.
- 不,说真的 - 来吧,你一定跳的很棒
I don't want to embarrass you guys.
我可不想让你们难堪
Just loosen up. Have some fun.
放松点,开心些
That's it.
就这样,对
Yeah.
很好
That's it.
就这样
- Guy really knows how to loosen up. - You're not kidding.
- 这家伙可真会放松 - 真不是开玩笑的
There he is.
他在那儿呢
Yes.
是啊
Unfortunately.
真不幸
For him.
对他来说
Shall we?
我们过去吧
I think it might be clobbering time.
我想舞厅差不多可以打烊了
Sue. What are you?
苏,你来...
General Hager.
哈格将军
Let's talk somewhere private.
我们找个没人的地方谈
Unless you need to do Jell-O shots off someone's stomach.
除非你想在谁的肚皮上玩鸡尾酒果冻
I was explaining to the girls about how the big bang led to...
我只是向女孩们解释 宇宙大爆炸,就这些…
This was Johnny's idea. I just went along.
这都是强尼的主意,我只是跟着来的
How does Reed know the general?
里德怎么会认识将军
A few years back, the guy was pushing a new missile-defense system.
几年前,五角大楼想建造新的 导弹防御体系
Reed testified that the technology wouldn't work.
里德证实了那技术不可行
I'm here on direct orders from the Joint Chiefs of Staff.
我在这里的唯一原因是 我收到参谋长联席会议的直接命令
Personally, I don't like sharing sensitive information with a civilian.
个人来说,我不喜欢和 平民科学家分享敏感信息
Especially one who enjoys the public spotlight so much.
其是那些非常喜欢抛头露脸的人
Always a pleasure to see you too, general.
见到你总是很荣幸,将军
What can I do for you?
我能为你做什么?
As you may know, there've been unusual occurrences.
你应该知道了 最近全球发生了一些不寻常的现象
Officially, we've downplayed their significance, but we're concerned...
官方已经尽量在公众中保持低调 但我们担心…
...these anomalies might pose a credible threat to our national security.
这些不正常现象 可能会对国家安全产生重大威胁
These were taken by one of our spy satellites three days ago.
这些是我们一颗卫星三天前拍摄到的
- What is it? - We hoped Dr. Richards could tell us.
- 这是什么? - 我们希望理查斯博士可以告诉我们
I'm afraid I've never seen anything like it. Ben?
我恐怕从未看到过类似的东西,本?
I would say that it was a meteor, but the trail's all wrong.
我本会以为那是颗陨石 但运行轨迹又完全不对
It's giving off its own energy.
这个东西本身具有动力源
Take a look at this.
再看看这个
These have been appearing in remote areas throughout the world.
这些是奇异事件开始后 地球一些偏远地区的情况
Field personnel estimate its diameter to be 200 meters.
地质勘探到这个洞直径大概有200米
To find out what this is about, we need a way to locate and intercept that object.
为了搞清楚这到底是怎么一回事 我们需要想办法定位并阻拦那个物体
A sensor could be tied into the Baxter Building's satellite grid.
我也许能建造一个感应器 和巴克斯特大楼的卫星网络连接
We can pinpoint the location of the object.
我们可以精确定位那个物体
- Good. You'll build the sensor for us... - I'm afraid I can't.
- 很好,你为我们制造感应器并连接到… - 恐怕不行
What?
什么?
I'm getting married this Saturday. I just don't have the time.
你看,我这周六就要结婚了,没有时间
Richards, your country needs your help.
理查斯,你的国家需要你的帮助
Call Professor Jeff Wagner.
你为什么不给杰夫·瓦格纳教授打电话
He's head of the Physics Department at Brown.
他是布朗大学物理系的主任 我肯定他能帮助你们的
I expected more, Richards.
我本来抱着更高的期望的,理查斯
Even from you.
就算是从你这种人身上
John Storm, Fantastic Four Incorporated.
强尼·史东,神奇四侠公司的
- Ever done any modeling? - Not interested.
- 你有做过职业模特吗? - 不感兴趣
- You got an amazing complexion. - Not interested.
- 因为你有非常好的条件 - 不感兴趣
Wow, and you just walked away.
哇,你就那么走了
I was definitely still talking.
我还没说完呢
I can't believe you just turned down a science project.
我真不敢相信你拒绝了一项科研计划
They can build a sensor without me.
没我他们也能造出一个感应器
The most important thing right now is our wedding.
目前最重要的事情就是我们的婚礼
No postponements. No interruptions.
不能延期,不能被打扰
Thank you.
谢谢
And, look, about what you saw back at the bar...
瞧,我希望你刚才在酒吧的看到的…
Don't worry about it. I know you.
别担心,我知道你的为人
I'm glad you had fun.
我很高兴你玩得开心
Thank you.
谢谢
Besides...
而且…
...it was nothing compared to what I did at my bachelorette party.
比起我在告别单身派对上做的事 你的那些根本不值一提
Talk about wild.
可以说是狂野
Wild?
狂野?
Come on.
快点
Hey, what are you doing up here?
嗨,你在上边干吗呢?
Nothing. Just needed some air.
没什么,就是透透气
You're making that thing for the general, aren't you?
你在给将军造那个机器,是吧?
I'm guessing Susie doesn't know anything about it.
我猜苏西还被蒙在鼓里吧
Don't worry, my lips are sealed.
别担心,我的嘴唇缝上了
That is, they would be if I had any.
虽然我根本没有嘴唇…
Look, don't tell Johnny.
别告诉强尼
- Don't tell Johnny what? - Great.
- 别告诉强尼什么? - 好极了
- Are you building that thing? - No.
- 你在造那个东西吗? - 不,只是…
If Sue finds out, you'll get an invisible kick in the nuts.
如果苏发现了 她肯定会隐身踢爆你老二的
- Hey, hey. We're keeping this quiet. - I know.
- 嘿,小声点别说出去 - 我明白
Don't worry.
别担心
It's the wedding of the century. Reed Richards and Susan Storm...
他们把这个称作"世纪婚礼" 里德·理查斯和苏珊·史东
...Mr. Fantastic and the Invisible Woman...
也被称为神奇先生和隐身女郎
...will try again to tie the knot today in a ceremony in New York.
将在今天在纽约举行庆典 正式结成连理
- Look at these parasites. - I know, it's unbelievable.
- 看看那些寄生虫 - 我明白,令人难以置信
Have they no shame?
不知羞耻
Hey! Hey, listen! Listen, everybody!
嘿,听着,所有人听着
This is a very special day for my sister, probably the most important of her life.
今天是我姐姐大喜的日子 是她一生中最重要的一天
So I just want to say to you guys, please respect our privacy.
我就想和大家说 请你们尊重我们的隐私
Come on, Johnny.
笑一个,强尼
Just kidding. We're auctioning off the exclusive wedding photos...
哈哈,开玩笑啦 我们将会把独家婚礼照片拍卖给出价最高的人
...to the highest bidder, so go online and place your bids. Thank you.
卖给出价最高的人,所以上网出价竞拍吧 谢谢你们
Johnny, are you planning...
强尼,你们计划…
So, what's it take to date the Human Torch?
那么,和霹雳火约会的需要些什么?
- Fireproof lingerie and a lot of aloe. - Thank you.
- 防火性感内衣,还有很多芦荟 - 谢谢
- Are you all right? - How are you?
- 最近好吗? - 你好吗?
Invitation, sir?
邀请函,先生?
I should be on that list.
我应该在那个名单上
- Name? - Stan Lee.
- 名字 - 史坦·李 (神奇四侠原作者)
Yeah, nice try, buddy.
真会编,老兄,真会编
- No, really. I'm Stan Lee. - Nice try.
- 不,不,不,真的,我是史坦·李 - 真会编
This isn't how I imagined it.
这不是我想像中的样子
It never is.
从来就和想像不一样
No, Alicia, it just doesn't feel right.
不,艾莉莎,就是感觉很不对
Sweetie...
宝贝儿…
...I think even superheroes are allowed to have wedding-day jitters.
我想就算是超级英雄 也会在结婚日胡思乱想的
It's more than that. Is my life always gonna be a circus?
不止是那样 难道我的生活将永远像个马戏团吗?
Do we really want to raise kids in all this?
我们真的想在这样环境下生儿育女吗?
Face it, we're not exactly normal.
面对现实吧,我们不是普通人
Ben and I aren't normal...
本和我也不是普通人
...but we don't let it get in the way of us being happy.
但我们不会让这 成为我们追求幸福的障碍
Do you love Reed?
你爱里德吗?
More than I've ever loved anyone.
胜过爱其他任何人
Then you have nothing to worry about.
那你就什么都不要担心
Thank you.
谢谢你
Okay.
好了
- Oh, great. - What?
- 哦,糟糕 - 怎么了?
I've got a zit.
我长了个暗疮
- Can't you put makeup on it? - No, no, I got it.
- 需要用妆补一补吗? - 不,不用,我能处理
Crisis averted.
危机解除
Now all I have to do is concentrate on the area for the next eight hours.
我现在要做的就是 全神贯注那个部位,坚持8个小时
Reed, come on. You're gonna miss your own wedding.
里德,快点,你快赶不及你的婚礼了
Just a minute.
等一下下
Almost done.
马上就完工
General, I'm putting the sensor online now.
将军,我现在就把感应器连接到网络
系统在线
There. If there's a surge in cosmic radiation anywhere, you'll know.
如果地球上任何地方发生宇宙辐射 你就会知道
Let's hope so. We've gotten reports of two more craters.
希望如此,理查斯 我们已经收到报告,又多了两个圆洞
Here comes the bride
新娘要来了
All right. Just linking it to my PDA.
好的,好的,我把这个 和我的PDA连在一起就好
- Reed. - And that's it.
- 里德 - 还有…成了
Good, that's great. Now shave and put on your tux.
好的,太好了! 现在你该刮胡子,穿礼服了
You're getting married and you look like a bum.
你快结婚了,却搞的象个叫花子
Absolutely.
没错
What?
怎么了?
I'm getting married.
我要结婚了
Oh, jeez.
噢,老天
I'm getting married.
我要结婚了
I heard of getting cold feet...
我听说过新娘落跑…
Okay.
很好
Hey, Johnny.
嘿,强尼
Does that amaze anyone else? How did she know it was me?
太令人吃惊了,她怎么会知道是我的? 我又没说话
To be honest, you kind of smell like ash.
说实话,你闻上去有股烟灰的味道
- You're late. - Let's not make today about me.
- 哈哈哈,你晚了 - 今天我可不是主角
It's Reed and Sue's big day.
今天是里德和苏的大日子
Let's give them the attention for a change.
我们应该转一转注意力了
Don't do that.
哦,别那么做
- Okay, you're perfect. - You're perfect.
- 你看上去完美极了 - 你也很完美
I'll see you upstairs.
待会楼上见
Bye, Johnny.
再见,强尼
So seems like you and Alicia are doing well. Annoyingly so, in fact.
看上去你和艾莉莎相处的很好 真是让人忌妒啊
Yeah, I'm a lucky guy.
是啊,我很幸运
Yeah, you are.
是啊
Question for you, though:
不过我有个问题
How do you guys?
你们两个是如何…
- None of your business! - Okay, I'm just concerned.
- 这不关你的事 - 好的,我是关心你嘛
I'd hate to find out she was killed in a rock slide.
我不想你早上醒来,发现她被落石砸死
I'll show you a rock slide!
我要让你看看什么才是落石
What are you?
你究竟是什么东西?
Thank you.
谢谢
Johnny?
强尼?
You shouldn't tease him so much.
你不应该总那么戏弄他
It was a joke.
只是开玩笑
I don't know, I think it bothers you to see him really happy and in love.
我不知道,我觉得你看到他沉浸在 爱的幸福之中,困扰了你
I think you're jealous.
我觉得你是嫉妒
You think I'm jealous? Have you seen the women I've dated?
你觉得我是嫉妒? 你看到我约会的女人了吗?
No.
没有
You can only fool yourself but for so long, Torch.
你只是在自欺欺人,霹雳火
Hey. It's the bride of stretchy man.
嘿,橡皮人的新娘来啦
- Don't start. - Don't listen to him. You look gorgeous.
- 别说了 - 别听他的,你看上去光彩照人
We'll see you out there, sweetie.
我们去外面等你,小甜心
- Come on. We're on. - Okay. Okay.
- 来吧,我们上 - 好的,好的
You don't look completely ridiculous in that dress.
你知道,你穿婚纱看上去并不那么可笑
Is that obnoxious-brother talk for "You look kind of nice"?
我的烦人弟弟是在说 "你看上去挺漂亮"的吗?
You look beautiful.
你看上去漂亮极了
Thank you.
谢谢
Dad would be proud.
爸爸会为你骄傲的
Yeah.
嗯
Reed, shut your cell phone off.
里德,把手机关了
Actually, this is a...
实际上,这是…
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here today to...
亲爱的朋友们 我们今天聚集于此是要…
Sue and Reed, congratulations on your wedding!
苏,里德,祝贺你们终成眷属
Where was I? Oh, yeah.
说到哪儿了?
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here today to join this couple...
亲爱的朋友们,我们今天聚集于此 来参加这对情侣
...Reed Richards and Susan Storm, together...
里德·理查斯先生和苏·史东女士一起…
...in the bond of holy...
缔结…神圣的…
(警报!宇宙辐射)
Matrimony.
婚姻…
I can't believe you brought that to our wedding.
真不敢相信 你把这东西带到我们婚礼上来了
I know, but there's a good reason.
我知道,但事出有因
- We have to do this quickly. - That's romantic.
- 我们必须尽快结束 - 那可真够浪漫
- Should I continue? - Yes, please.
- 我可以继续吗 - 是的,请继续
- There are many kinds of love. - Could you skip to the end, please?
- 世上有很多种爱 - 能直接说结尾吗?
- Reed. - Excuse me?
- 里德 - 怎么?
- What happened? - What's going on?
- 出什么事了? - 这是怎么了?
We've lost power! We're going down! We're going down!
我们失去动力 我们要坠毁了,我们要坠毁了
It's too late.
太晚了
- Pull up! - I'm trying! I'm trying!
- 拉升啊,拉升啊 - 我在努力,我在努力
Ben!
本
- Johnny. - This is Dolce.
- 强尼 - 这衣服可是杜嘉班纳的（著名服装品牌）
Flame on!
点火
Man, he's fast.
伙计,他真快
That is cool.
哦,好酷
- Hey, taxi! - Oh, man!
- 嘿,出租车 - 哦
Showoff.
游戏结束
Time to end this.
是时候结束了
Can we talk?
我们能谈一谈吗?
Okay, you win.
好吧,你赢了
Flame on! Come on!
点火!快点
Flame on!
点火
Hey.
嘿
Your herald summons you.
你的主人召唤你
Another world awaits.
另一个世界还在等着你
Let it be done quickly.
让它尽快结束吧
It looked like a man, but completely covered in silver, and it flew this, like...
他看上去像人类,但是全身被银装 而且用来飞的道具就象…
...surfboard-type thing. I know that sounds crazy.
象冲浪板一样的东西 我知道听上去很疯狂
Oh, no, not at all.
不,一点也不
Did you follow the shiny man to Lollipop Land or the Rainbow Junction?
那你跟着闪光人飞到了"糖果大地" 去了"彩虹尽头"喽
- I know what I saw. - Thank you. It's all right, Johnny.
- 我知道我看到了什么 - 谢谢,没关系,强尼
Whatever this thing is, it has the ability to convert matter and energy.
无论这东西的到底是什么 它都有将物质和能量转换的能力
So it caused the anomalies?
所以是它引起了奇怪现象
It seems to radiate cosmic energy when it exerts itself...
看上去好像他发力时会发出宇宙辐射
...randomly affecting matter. Evidently, this entity, this...
并随机影响物质 很显然,这个实体…
...Silver Surfer...
这个银色冲浪手
...didn't want to be detected. It destroyed the sensor.
不想被探测到,所以摧毁了感应器
- It knew it was being monitored? - And traced it back here.
- 他知道被监测到了 - 而且追踪到了这里
We're dealing with something highly resourceful.
我们对付的东西有高度智慧
Are you feeling okay?
你还好吧?
Yeah. I just... I gotta walk this off.
没事,我去走走就好了
We must destroy it before it attacks again.
在它再次攻击前,我们必须摧毁它
Richards, find me another way to track it.
理查斯,用别的办法找到它
Sue, I am so sorry.
苏,真的太抱歉了
I didn't tell you, because I didn't want you to worry.
我没告诉你的原因是不想让你担心
I'm not mad you built the sensor. You did the right thing.
我不是生气你制造了感应器 这没错
Oh, great.
哦,太好了
I wasn't finished.
我还没说完
Okay. Sorry. Please continue.
好的,对不起,请继续
This proves what I've been saying.
瞧,这证明了我一直在说的
Could you drop the force field?
你能去掉这个能量场吗
We can't even... Sorry.
我们不能连…对不起
Even our wedding turns into World War III.
我们不能连婚礼搞成了第三次世界大战
I know. But once we are married, everything will be back to normal.
我知道,但是一旦我们结婚了 所有的事情都会趋于正常的
We will never have normal lives as long as we do what we do.
只要我们继续从事这项事业 我们永远都不能过正常的生活
How could we possibly raise a family like this?
我们怎么可能这样组成一个家庭呢
I'm gonna go check on Johnny.
我去看看强尼
Johnny?
强尼?
Hey, are you all right, pal?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
嘿,你还好吧老弟?
Johnny?
强尼?
Johnny, are you okay?
强尼你没事吧?
I don't know. I've been feeling really strange since my run-in with surfer boy.
我不知道,和冲浪手接触后感觉很奇怪
Maybe we should get you checked out.
也许我们应该给你检查一下
- Why did you do that? - I didn't do anything!
- 你为什么这么做 - 我什么都没做
Stop, drop and roll! Stop, drop and roll!
别动,快倒地翻滚 别动,快倒地翻滚
Oh, my God, Sue! Just...
噢,天啊,苏,快…
Just hang on! I'll get you, okay?
坚持住,我来帮你
Flame on!
点火
Hey, watch it.
嘿,看着点
Reed!
里德
Reed! Reed!
里德,里德
- Help! - Sue?
- 救命啊 - 苏?
I'm on fire!
我着火了
- Sue! What's going on? - I'm on fire!
- 苏,出什么事了? - 我着火了
- You're on fire! - You think?
- 你着火了 - 你觉得呢?
- Hold on! - Pull me in!
- 坚持住 - 拉我进去
Hey, it's the Human Torch!
嘿,是霹雳火
Johnny!
强尼
- I'm not Johnny! - Sue, how did this happen?
- 我不是强尼 - 苏,怎么会这样?
I touched Johnny, and then this.
我摸了下强尼就变成这样了
- Where is Johnny? - Here.
- 强尼在哪 - 在这里
Try it again.
再碰一次
- Nice. - There you go.
- 很好 - 看这里
Hey, get out of there.
嘿,让开
Sue, your clothes.
苏,你的衣服
Why does this always happen to me?
为什么这种事总发生在我身上
All of Sue's results are normal.
苏的所有结果都正常
But Johnny's...
不过强尼的…
Johnny's are what?
强尼的怎么了?
Your encounter with the Surfer put your molecules in a constant state of flux.
你和冲浪手的接触导致了你的分子结构 不稳定,持续波动中
Is that bad?
那很糟糕吗?
It caused you to temporarily switch powers with Sue.
那让你暂时和苏交换了能力
- I'd like to run more tests and... - Want a volunteer?
- 我要多做点测试就更理想了 - 需要志愿者吗?
- No, no, hey! - No, no, no!
- 不不不不,嘿 - 不要,不要,不要
No, no, hey! This is serious!
不,不要,嗨,这是很严肃的事情
I just wanted to give him a hug.
我只是想抱抱他
We don't know the extent of his condition.
我们还不知道他状况到了什么地步
It could be progressive.
可能恶化,也可能好转
- It could be fun. - No, Ben!
- 可能会很好玩 - 不要啊,本
Ben!
本
Hey. Hey, it's me! I'm back!
嘿,嘿,是我,我回来了
Oh, my God!
噢,我的老天
Come on! We just said this is serious!
拜托,我们刚说过这是很严肃的
Oh, yeah, serious.
哦,是的,严肃的
Oh, you gotta be kidding me!
噢,你一定是耍我玩呢
- Hey, not bad. - Incredible.
- 嘿,不错啊 - 难以置信
- You better be able to fix this! - I'm right on it.
- 里德,你最好把这搞定 - 我会马上动手的
- Ben, stop it! - I see why you like that.
- 本,别这样 - 我开始明白你为什么喜欢那样了
Oh, no, no, no.
噢,别,别,别,别
Crap.
真垃圾
That's not funny. What am I supposed to do in the meantime?
那一点都不好玩 现在我该怎么做
Just try to keep your distance from us.
尽量和我们保持距离
You and me are gonna be spending a whole lot of time together, pal!
咱们将会一起相处很长一段时间的,老弟
My inside sources tell me unlucky bride-to-be Sue Storm...
我的内部线人透露 不幸的准新娘的苏·史东
...turned invisible and is staying that way...
在昨天让人难堪的事件中隐身后
...after yesterday's embarrassing fiasco.
持续人间蒸发中
Next, the Invisible Woman's greatest fashion blunders...
接下来播放激动人心的 隐形女出糗时尚秀
...and an impromptu dance routine from former scientist Reed Richards.
以及前任科学家里德·理查斯 表演的即兴舞蹈
Why do you keep watching this? Just ignore it.
你为什么老是要看这些,别理他们
I can't ignore it, Reed. There's no getting away from it!
我没法不看,里德 根本无处可逃
- I believe there is. - How?
- 我相信会有办法的 - 怎么做?
See? No answer.
看啊,没办法
Yes, there is.
有的
What if, after this crisis is over...
假如,这次危机结束后…
- ...we leave it all behind? - What are you talking about?
- 我们把所有的都抛开 - 你想说什么?
We move out of the Baxter Building.
我们搬出巴克斯特大厦
I'll take a teaching position somewhere.
我去从教
Get back to my research.
还是做回我的研究工作
The two of us will live our lives and raise a family, like normal people.
我们两个会有自己的生活 组成家庭,就象普通人一样
You would do that?
你愿意那么做吗?
Nothing is more important to me than our future together.
对我来说我们的未来才是最重要
Oh, thank you.
哦,谢谢
What about Ben and Johnny?
那本和强尼怎么办?
They'll understand.
他们会理解的
Besides, Johnny's always been more of a solo act.
而且,强尼更喜欢单打独斗
Let's not mention it to them yet.
我们先别和他们说
Johnny's got enough to worry about as it is, with his power problems.
强尼最近对于他能力的问题 已经够操心的了
(格棱兰岛 罗素冰河)
You've been busy, my friend.
你最近很忙啊,我的朋友
Your talents are impressive.
你的才华让人印象深刻
Can you understand what I'm saying?
你能听懂我说的话吗?
Together, we could be unstoppable.
我们在一起,将无人能敌
Anything would be ours for the taking.
为所欲为
All that you know is at an end.
你所认知的都将被终结
What do you mean by that?
你什么意思?
Wait! I said, wait!
等等,我说了,等等
They're breaking up the team. Reed and Sue, I overheard them.
他们要解散队伍 里德和苏,我刚偷听到的
They want a nice, normal, boring-ass life.
他们想过美好普通无聊之极的生活
- No more Fantastic Four. - Well...
- 神奇四侠将不复存在了 - 那…
...what do we do? Keep going, just the two of us?
我们怎么办 就剩我们两个干下去吗?
And call ourselves what? The Dynamic Duo?
我们管自己叫什么,爆破双人组?
When were they gonna tell us?
他们要什么时候才告诉我们
They'll tell you when they're ready.
他们准备好了就会告诉你们的
It's their decision, not yours.
这是他们的决定 不是你们的
You can't be mad at them for doing what makes them happy.
你们不能因为他们 追求自己的幸福而生气
Guys.
伙计们
We've got a serious problem.
咱们有大麻烦了
I cross-referenced the Surfer's radiation through every astronomical database.
我在每个天文数据库里面 对冲浪手辐射进行了比较
Altair 7, Rigel 3, Vega 6.
牵牛星7号,参宿七3号,织女星6号
- He's been to all these planets? - And now they're lifeless.
- 他去过所有的那些星球? - 现在那里已经毫无生命迹象了
Barren. Some even shattered.
荒芜,有些甚至破碎了
Everywhere the Surfer goes, eight days later, the planet dies.
冲浪手去过的地方 八天后,所到星球就死亡了
How are we gonna stop him?
我们怎样才能阻止他
We don't even know where he is.
我们甚至不知道他在哪里
What about the craters?
那些坑洞呢?
They appear in a numerical sequence.
它们的出现是有规律可循的
The last crater was formed in Greenland...
最近的一个坑洞在格陵兰岛
...so the next in the sequence should be...
那么下个坑洞应该在…
...latitude 51 degrees, 30 minutes north...
北纬51度30分
...Iongitude zero degrees, seven minutes west.
西经0度7分
When he surfaces, move the fight away from the crowd.
当冲浪手出现时 我们要远离人群才开战
He's too fast to contain. When I see silver, I'm hitting him!
他太快了,根本控制不住 我一看到他,就立刻展开攻击
You can't do that. We stick to the plan and work as a team.
你不能那么做 要按照计划,集体行动
Oh, we're a team now? News to me.
我们现在是个团队啊 对我来说真是新鲜
- What are you talking about? - You know what.
- 你在说什么? - 你知道我在说什么
We were gonna tell you.
我们会告诉你们的
- When? When you moved our stuff out? - Johnny, this isn't a good time.
- 什么时候?你搬出巴克斯特大厦的时候? - 强尼,现在不是吵架的时候
Kid's got a point, Reed. You should have told us.
这孩子说的有道理,里德 你们该告诉我们的
That's enough! We'll talk about this later.
好吧,好吧,说够了吧 我们以后再谈
What the hell is wrong with you people?
你们到底他妈的出什么问题了
It's a whirlpool!
是旋涡
Oh, my God.
噢,我的天
What is that?
那怎么回事
Get out! Get out!
快离开,快离开
Don't let go!
别放手
- Move! - Come on! Go!
- 走啊 - 快跑,跑啊
No, Johnny!
不要啊,强尼
Guys? What are you doing?
伙计们,你们在干什么?
Ben! Lift it higher!
本,抬高点
I'll try.
我会尽力的
Sue!
苏
Stay back, before you get somebody killed.
靠后站 在你害死人之前
Oh, my God.
哦,我的天啊
What the hell was that?
那他妈的是什么?
We'll make adjustments. Next time, we'll be ready.
我们要调整一下 下一次,我们会准备好的
Next time? There's no next time.
下一次?没有下一次了
You can't handle this alone. I'm bringing in help.
你们不可能单独处理好这件事 这就是为什么我要找人帮忙
Bringing in soldiers and weaponry will put innocent people in danger.
将军,你投入更多的兵力 就让更多无辜的人身处险境
No more than you already have.
不会比你造成的多
Victor?
维特?
What's the matter? Afraid of ghosts?
怎么了?你怕鬼吗?
- Look out! - Don't move!
- 小心 - 不许动
Since you're a ghost, you won't mind if I break your neck.
既然你是鬼魂 一定不介意我拧断你的小脖子吧
- Let him go. - You know who that is?
- 放开他 - 你知道他是谁吗
Victor von Doom. He's here under my orders.
维特·方·杜姆,是我的部下
Ben, let him go.
本,放开他
How is this possible?
这怎么可能?
How are you still alive?
他怎么还活着?
No thanks to you four, that's for certain.
那当然得多亏了你们四个啊
Von Doom's made contact with the alien. He's got valuable information.
方·杜姆和外星人有过接触 掌握着有价值的情报
Information that might just help save the planet.
也许能拯救地球的情报
Now let's be clear about this...
我们先把话说明白
...shall we? I hate you.
好吗?我恨你
All of you.
你们全部
But the world's at stake and we need to work together to survive.
但世界危在旦夕 我们要同心协力才能生存
General, we know firsthand, you trust Victor and you're gonna regret it.
将军,我们有亲身体会 你若信任维特,必将后悔的
So far, the only one I've regretted trusting here is you, Richards.
目前为止,我后悔信任的人是你,理查斯
Reed, don't agree to this.
里德,别答应他们
Let's see what he's got.
咱们看看他知道什么
I made a detailed recording of our little encounter.
对于我们的接触过程 我做了详细的纪录
All that you know is at an end.
你所认知的都将被终结
Well?
怎么样?
I like the part where he knocks you on your ass.
我喜欢他把你的屁股 摔得稀巴烂那部分
Look at where the energy levels surge when he attacks me.
看看他攻击我时的能量的流动情况
There? See what happened?
那里,就是那样发生的
The energy was channeled through him, but it originated from his board.
能量从他身体流过 但是从源于他的冲浪板
If we can separate him from the board, we can cut off his power completely.
如果我们能把他和冲浪板分开 我们就能完全切断他的能量来源
- That's what we have to do. - How?
- 那就是我们必须做的 - 怎么做?
If I knew that, I wouldn't need you people, would I?
如果我知道,还要你们干吗?
You two should get started right away.
你们两个现在就应该开始了
I'm glad we have the opportunity to collaborate again.
我很高兴我们有机会再度合作
I'll try to talk slowly so you can keep up.
我会尽量说慢点 你好跟得上了
How can we be working on the same side as Victor?
我们怎么可以和维特是一边的
You got me. Things were simpler when I could just whale on the guy.
我很无语,兄弟 如果我抽他,事情就会简单得多
What's he doing? A fire.
他在干吗?着火了
Look at that.
看啊
I'll pay for that.
我会赔的
I'll tell you, Ben, I'm starting to feel like a complete screw-up.
告诉你,本 我开始觉得自己是个废物了
Hey, hey, you're not a complete screw-up.
嘿,你不是个废物
Thank you.
谢谢
Look, kid, it's out of our hands. It's up to the eggheads now.
瞧啊,伙计,现在不是我们说了算了 现在取决于理论家们了
You think Reed's right about the whole end-of-the-world thing?
你觉得里德是对的吗? 关于世界末日的事
He's never been wrong about this kind of thing before.
他对这种事从来没错过
You know, I'm not exactly a deep kind of guy.
你知道的,我不是那种懂科技的人
Really?
是吗?
But if Reed's right, and this is it...
但如果里德是对的,这就是末日了
...how do you want to spend your last few minutes?
你生命的最后几分钟打算怎么过?
Part of me would like to go out fighting.
部分的我想出去打架
But the truth is...
但事实上…
...I'd like to spend my last couple of minutes holding Alicia.
我想与艾莉莎相拥度过生命中的最后时光
That sounds pretty good.
听上去很不错
I mean, not the "holding Alicia" thing. She's your girlfriend, not mine.
我的不是说抱着艾莉莎的事情 你的女朋友,不是我的
Want nothing to do with her. Not to say she's not attractive.
我不想对她干什么 不是说她没有吸引力
She's very attractive. She's so attractive.
她非常迷人 她,你知道的,太迷人了
Even with the... I can't think of a guy that wouldn't want to...
就算(失明),你知道的 想像不到哪一个男人不想…
What I meant...
我的意思是…
...was that it's nice to have somebody.
能和一个人在一起真好
Well, you got me, pal.
好吧,我无语了,兄弟
How's it going?
进展如何?
I can't find a link.
我毫无头绪
- It'll be all right. - No, it won't!
- 会没事的,你拥有所有... - 不会的
The whole world's counting on me, and I just...
整个世界都指望着我呢 而我却…
Reed, you're gonna find the answer.
里德,你会找到答案的
- You always do. - Thanks, Sue.
- 你总能找到 - 是啊,谢谢,苏
- You just need to relax. - Yeah, right.
- 你需要休息放松. - 是啊,说的对
You do. Reed, you need to relax.
是真的,里德,你需要放松
Take a deep breath.
深呼吸
Slower.
慢慢的
There you go.
做的不错
Come on. Again.
来啊,再做一次
See? I can already feel your pulse slowing down.
看啊,我已经能感觉到你脉搏慢了下来
- Do you remember that time... - A pulse.
- 你记得上次… - 脉冲
A tachyon pulse.
速子脉冲
I love you.
我爱你
I'm glad I could help.
很高兴我可以帮上忙
So exactly how does this thing work?
那么,这个东西具体怎么工作的?
When we activate the field, it'll separate him from his board making him powerless.
我们激活他周围的场,这会让他 和冲浪板分开,从而失去能量
Like a fish in a net.
就象落网之鱼
- Yeah. - Yeah.
- 是的 - 是的
- In theory, anyway. - How long until it's operational?
- 理论上是,不管怎么说 - 还需要多久可以付之实施
- Three hours. - Three hours.
- 3小时 - 3小时
I can only go so fast, since I'm working by myself.
我知道,我自己一个人 只能做到这么快
- What do you need to make this happen? - There are a couple of things.
- 要实现它,你还需要什么? - 实际上还有几样东西
Do your field engineers have a beryllium casing?
你的工程师们有辐射保护服吗?
What are you doing?
你在做什么?
- Don't you knock? - You're supposed to be helping Reed.
- 你有敲门吗? - 你应该在实验室里帮里德
Tell him not to worry.
告诉他不用担心
I'll be there to hold his hand and finish his little project for him.
我会去牵着他的小手 帮他完成他的小项目的
- Anything else? - How'd you do it?
- 还有别的事吗? - 你怎么做到的?
How did you come back?
你怎么活过来的?
It scares you, doesn't it?
吓着你了,是吧?
The things I can do.
我做的事
Did you know I could create a force field inside someone's body...
你知道我能在 人的体内制造一个能量场
...and expand it until they explode?
然后让它膨胀直到它爆炸吗?
Give it your best shot.
试试看啊
Just get back to the lab.
快回实验室去
Mr. Storm?
史东先生?
We're heading to intercept the Surfer in 10 minutes, with or without you.
我们10分钟后开始拦截冲浪手 有没有你都无所谓
Were you waiting outside the bathroom to try and catch me in a towel?
你刚才是不是就在浴室门外 等着看我围着浴巾的样子?
That was a joke. I was joking.
开玩笑,我开玩笑呢
Why are you so down on me? You don't even know me.
你为什么对我这么冷淡? 你甚至都不了解我
I know you very well. I read your personality profile.
实际上我很了解你 我读过你的个人档案
Confident. Reckless. Irresponsible.
自负,鲁莽,不负责任
Self-obsessed, bordering on narcissism.
自恋已极
Okay, so you do know me.
好吧,你确实了解我
All I've seen is a guy that almost got his team killed.
我所看到的就是一个 差点害死自己团队的人
Okay.
好吧
I've been a little off my game lately.
我最近有点不在状态
This is not a game.
这不是游戏
(德国 黑森林)
- Sir, he's in position north of here. - Good.
- 长官,他已经在北面就位 - 很好
- General, give us a one-mile perimeter. - Forget it, Richards.
- 将军,给我一个周长一公里的区域 - 你就别想了,理查斯
You had your shot and you blew it. This is a military operation now.
我给你过机会,你搞砸了 现在这是军事行动了
Jam the signal, get out of the way, and let us do our job.
你只管扰乱信号 让开路,其它的我们来
- You don't understand. - No, you don't understand.
- 你不明白 - 不,是你不明白
So let me make it clear for you and your pack of freaks.
让我把话给你 和你们这帮怪物说清楚
I'm the quarterback. You're on my team.
我才是四分卫,而你在我的队伍里
Got it?
明白了吗?
But I guess you never played football in high school, did you, Richards?
我猜你高中里从来没打过橄榄球 是吧,理查斯
No, you're right, I didn't.
没错,你说的对,我没打过橄榄球
I stayed in and studied, like a good little nerd.
我就像普通的小书呆子一样埋头苦学
And fifteen years later...
然而15年后
...I'm one of the greatest minds of the 21 st century.
我成为了21世纪最有智慧的人之一
I'm engaged to the hottest girl on the planet.
我和星球上最性感的女孩订婚了
And the jock who played quarterback in high school...
而高中打橄榄球四分卫的大个子
...is right in front of me, asking me for my help.
他站在我面前,请求我的帮助
And I say he's not gonna get a damn thing...
而我告诉他 他妈的什么也别想得到
...unless he does exactly what I tell him to...
除非他完全照我说的去做
...and starts treating my friends and me with some respect.
而且开始学会如何尊重我和我的朋友
Give him what he wants.
他要什么就给他
I am so hot for you right now.
我现在觉得你性感极了
Me too.
我也这么觉得,是不是,里德
This is it.
就是这里了
You have your coordinates. Set up your posts and rendezvous back here.
你们有各自的坐标 安置好你们的脉冲仪,然后回来汇合
First squad, move out!
第一小队,前进
Hey. You scared me there, Smokey. Look at you. You're cute.
你吓到我了,小灰 看看你,长得真可爱啊
Yeah, that's right. Keep running, Boo Boo.
那就对了,不要停,布布
Overgrown furball.
不中用的大毛球
- What's our status? - Yeah. I'm good to go.
- 你的情况怎么样? - 很好,我快好了
- Same here. - Almost there.
- 我也是 - 就好了
Guys?
伙计们?
- We have a problem. - What's wrong?
- 我们有麻烦了 - 怎么了?
He's here.
他在这里
Get out of there, right now!
快离开,马上
Why are you destroying our planet?
你为什么要毁灭我们的星球?
I have no choice.
我别无选择
- Sue! - Wait!
- 苏 - 等等
What do you mean, you don't have a choice?
你说你别无选择是什么意思?
There's always a choice.
总有别的选择的
Not always.
不总是
Why are you trying to destroy us?
你为什么想毁灭我们?
I am not the Destroyer.
我不是毁灭者
Come on, Richards. Jam the damn signal.
快点啊,理查斯 他妈的快扰乱信号啊
Maybe he needs a little persuasion.
也许需要催催他
- Fire one over the top. - Roger, out.
- 发射一枚导弹 - 收到,开火
- Open fire. - Open fire.
- 开火 - 开火
Open fire! Repeat, open fire!
开火,重复,开火
Fall back! Fall back!
后撤,后撤
- Let me just... - No, wait!
- 让我… - 不,等一下
Reed.
里德
Come on, Sue.
快点啊,苏
All right, it's up.
好了,启动了
Reed.
里德
Got him.
逮住他了
Not so tough now, are you?
看你再牛逼
Victor! Stay back!
维特,退后
You're the quarterback.
你是四分卫
Eyes on! Keep your weapons trained!
看着点,保持待机
- Perimeter secure! - Move him out.
- 防区安全 - 带他走
(西伯利亚 雅库茨克)
- Open the gate! - Get him to the debriefing room.
- 开门 - 把他带到审讯室
- We had an agreement. - Calm down.
- 将军,我们有协议的 - 冷静点
The enemy has been captured.
敌人被抓住了,任务完成了
- Where is he? - Contained.
- 他在哪? - 关起来了
General?
将军
Mr. Sherman.
沙曼先生
If you'll excuse us, we have work to do.
失陪了,我们有事情要做
- I want to be there for the questioning. - Not gonna happen.
- 我想参加审讯 - 恐怕不行
Make sure our guests remain here, comfortably.
请保证我们的客人呆在这里 舒舒服服的
Yes, sir.
遵命,长官
General, what about the board?
将军,冲浪板怎么处理?
It's in a chamber which continuously scrambles the signal.
它在一间不停放出干扰信号的房间里
There are certain things I'm not permitted to do...
有些事不允许我做
...because they're considered human-rights violations.
出于他们对倾犯人权的顾虑
Fortunately, you're not human.
幸运的是,你不是人类
Are we prisoners?
我们是囚犯吗?
How did that happen?
怎么会这样
Apparently, they don't want us interfering with their methods.
很明显,他们不希望我们 干涉他们的审讯手段
I can't imagine what they're doing to him.
我都不敢想像他们会对他做出什么
- I say he gets what he deserves. - How can you say that?
- 我说他罪有应得 - 你怎么可以那么说?
I'm just saying maybe the general's right about this.
我只是说,将军说的有可能是对的
The guy was about to destroy the planet. He said so himself.
他就是要毁灭地球的 他自己这么说的
It doesn't make sense. He protected me from the missile. Why would he do that?
但是没有道理啊,他保护我不被导弹伤害 他为什么要那么做?
Maybe he thinks you're cute.
也许他觉得你很可爱
There's more going on. He said he wasn't the Destroyer.
还有别的,他说他不是毁灭者
Maybe he lied?
也许他在说谎
We need to get inside there and talk to him.
我们需要进去和他谈谈
But under the radar.
但不能被发现
Is there any way we could get some DVDs...
能不能给我们弄个DVD
...or popcorn or something?
- I'll call it in. - Great.
- 我会搞定的,史东先生 - 太棒了
Thank you. Semper fi.
谢谢,水兵
That's the Marine Corps. We're the Army.
那是海军的叫法,我们是陆军
Right, I know it's the Army.
对啊,我明白了,陆军
Captain Raye. Access granted.
雷上尉,准许进入
General.
将军
Von Doom wants to speak with you.
方·杜姆想和你谈谈
You should really be a little more cooperative.
你实在应该更合作一些
Mr. Sherman, let's take a break.
沙曼先生,我们休息一下
I know you are there.
我知道你在那里
What's your name?
你叫什么名字?
Come on, you must have a name.
好啦,你一定有名字的
I'm Susan.
我叫苏珊
You said you weren't the one trying to destroy our world. Then who is?
你说你不是想摧毁我们星球的人 那又是谁?
- The one I serve. - Who do you serve?
- 我的主人 - 你的主人是谁?
I'm trying to help you, but to do that, you have to tell me the truth.
听着,我在尽量帮助你 但要那样做,你必须告诉我真相
Please.
求你了
It is known by many names. My people called it...
它有很多名字,我的人民管它叫…
...Galactus...
加拉特斯…
...the Devourer of Worlds.
世界的毁灭者
It must feed on energy to survive.
它必须吞噬能量才能生存
Both thermal...
包括热能
...and organic.
电能和有机物
How can you serve this thing?
你怎么能侍奉这种东西
Because I must.
因为我必须这么做
Doesn't it bother you, all the worlds and innocent people you've helped destroy?
你能心安理得吗, 所有那些世界 那些无辜的人,你都是帮凶啊
My service spares my world...
我的侍奉,可以让我的世界幸免遇难
...and the one I love.
还有我的爱人
Why did you try to protect me?
你为什么试图保护我?
Because...
因为…
...you remind me of her.
你让我想起了她
Could you stop the Destroyer if you wanted to?
如果你愿意 你能阻止那个毁灭者吗?
It is not I who draws the Destroyer here. It is the beacon.
不是我把毁灭者带到这里的 是灯塔
What's the beacon?
灯塔是什么?
The source of my power.
我能量的来源
Your board?
你的冲浪板?
Take joy in the last few hours you have left...
享受你生命中最后的几个小时吧
...for he is nearly here.
因为大难已临头
Well? I helped deliver the alien to you, as promised.
好了,我已经履行我的承诺 帮你们抓住了外星人
Now it's time to keep your end of the bargain.
现在该你履行承诺了
You can do your tests on the board...
你可以拿冲浪板做实验
...but under armed guard and in my presence only.
但是要守卫看着,而且我必须在场
Absolutely.
当然
General Hager. Access granted.
哈格将军,准许进入
The board draws it here.
冲浪板正指引着它来这里
How do you fight something that eats planets?
我们怎么能和吞噬星球的东西对抗呢
We have to get to the board and lead it away from here.
我们必须找到冲浪板 把它引向别的地方,趁现在还来得及
Well, do you think the general will go for that?
好吧,你觉得将军会同意吗?
He'll have no choice.
他没的选择
Thank you, general.
谢谢,将军
But I'm afraid...
但我恐怕…
...the truth is...
真相是…
...sometimes Reed is right.
有时里德是对的
What...
什么?
Hey, you. Come here.
嘿,你过来
Let me ask you something.
我有事要问你
Nice.
棒极了
Crap.
哦,见鬼
Ben!
本
Okay, that one hurt.
喔,真疼
- Where's Reed? - Back here.
- 里德在哪里? - 在后面
My bad.
我的错
Reed.
里德
Victor. We've gotta get it back.
维特…我们要把他抓回来
We need to get the Surfer. He understands its power.
我们需要带上冲浪手 他是唯一懂得如何运用冲浪板能量的人
Even if we break him out of this place, how are we gonna catch up to Victor?
即使我们把他带出这里 怎么才能追上维特?
Leave that to me.
那就交给我了
- Halt! - Stay where you are!
- 停下 - 呆在那不许动
Pal, this is the luckiest day of your life.
老兄,你行大运了
What the hell is going on? Where is General Hager?
这里到底发生了什么,哈格将军呢?
He's dead.
他死了
And if we don't get him out of here, we'll all be.
如果我们不带他出去,我们都会死
Frankie...
法兰其…
...the world is literally at stake here. You have to trust us.
世界已经危在旦夕了 你必须相信我们
Please.
求你了
We need to get to the roof. It should be here by now.
我们要到屋顶上去,它现在应该到了
What should be here?
什么东西?
Holy crap!
我的天啊
Reed.
里德
This is by far the coolest thing you have ever done.
这是目前为止你做的最酷的东西
- Hemi? - Of course.
- 半自动的? - 当然
Okay, Ben, you get inside. Johnny, you fly behind us.
好了,本你进去 强尼,你飞在我们后面
- You gotta let me fly this. - I'm the best pilot. I should drive.
- 你得让我驾驶这玩意 - 别想了,我是最好的飞行员,我来开
- Guys. - You're lucky if it can carry you.
- 伙计们 - 你说真的吗?这东西能装下你已经是运气了
- I can fly circles around you. - Guys!
- 我能开着围着你兜圈子 - 伙计们
- Reed. - Shut up! And move it!
- 里德 - 闭嘴,快上去
I'm driving.
我来开
Flame on!
点火
Okay. We're now officially enemies of the United States of America.
好啦,我们现在正式成为美国公敌了
Victor is out there somewhere with unlimited power.
维特在某个地方,拥有无限的力量
And we've got a giant intergalactic force...
我们还有个强大的星系怪兽
...that's about to destroy our planet in less than 24 hours. Did I miss anything?
想在不到24小时里摧毁我们的星球 我漏了什么吗?
I've locked on Victor's energy trail. He's headed over Southeast China.
我已经锁定了维特的能量轨迹 他正飞往中国东南部
Hang on.
坐稳了
Norrin Radd.
诺林·拉德
- What? - I was once called Norrin Radd.
- 什么? - 我以前的名字叫诺林·拉德
Norrin, we'll need your help to save our world.
诺林,我们需要你帮助我们 来拯救我们的星球
Do you understand?
你明白吗?
What the hell was that?
那是他妈是什么?
Victor, the board is drawing the Destroyer here. You have to give it up.
维特,这个冲浪板正引导着毁灭者来这里 你必须放弃它
You know, I've never been the giving type, Reed.
你知道 我从来都不是会放弃的人,里德
Hold on!
抓稳了
We're sitting ducks!
我们是瓮中之鳖
We're gonna have to split up!
我们必须分开
- What? - This ought to be fun!
- 什么? - 那会很有趣的
He's really pissing me off!
他把我逼急了
Surf's up, metalhead!
大浪来了,金属脑袋
Victor, only the Surfer can stop the Destroyer. But he needs his board.
维特,只有冲浪手才能阻止毁灭者 但他需要冲浪板
- Come and get it, Richards. - Victor.
- 自己来拿啊,理查斯 - 维特
Let's all go for a spin!
让我们转起来吧
Norrin!
诺林
Catch.
抓到你了
Sue!
苏
Oh, my God.
噢,我的天啊
Sue. Sue.
苏,苏
- Oh, God. - Johnny, don't touch her!
- 噢,老天啊 - 强尼,别碰她
Oh, God. Oh, God.
哦,天啊,哦,天啊
You need to find a way to get the board.
你需要想办法弄到冲浪板
- Sue, I... - Okay.
- 苏,我… - 行
He is here.
他到了
Reed?
里德?
Reed.
里德
Victor's gotta have a pulse emitter linking him to his board.
维特一定是通过脉冲发射器 和冲浪板连接的
We take it out, we can separate him from his board.
我们把发射器破坏 就可以把他和冲浪板分开
He's too strong for me.
他对我来说太强大了
I could whale on him if I get close...
我能打败他,如果我可以靠近点的话
...but he could see me coming from a mile away.
但是他能从一公里外看到我
It would take all of us.
那就我们就一起上
Or maybe just one of us.
也许我们中的一个就够了
We don't know what it could do to you.
我们不知道这会对你产生什么影响
Let's not make this about me.
现在不是担心我的时候
To quote a friend of mine...
用我一个朋友的话说
...it's clobbering time.
狂欢时间到了
You ain't going down fighting, kid.
你不能独自战斗,小家伙
Not without me.
没我可不行
You've gotta go.
你该走了
Treasure each moment with her.
珍惜和她在一起的每一刻.
And tell her she was right.
告诉她,她是对的
We do have a choice.
我们确实可以选择
Thought you could use a hand.
我想你可能需要我帮你一把
Oh, my God.
噢,天啊
Why isn't it working?
怎么不起作用?
We were too late.
我们晚了
I will no longer serve.
我不再侍奉你了
This is the end for us both.
我们将同归于尽
Hi.
嗨
What did I miss?
我错过什么了吗?
Hey! Hey!
嘿! 嘿!
- He did it. - Great job, kid.
- 他做到了 - 干得好,小家伙
Hey, wait. I'm not changing.
等等,我不会变化了
Hey, that's right.
嘿,是啊
Great.
太棒了
Okay, now you're making me uncomfortable.
好吧,你让我感到不习惯了
So I guess this is it.
那么我想一切都结束了
We all go our separate ways.
我们该各走各的了
No.
不
- No? - No.
- 不是吗? - 不是
- No? - Lf not for the team...
- 不会吗? - 如果不是整个队伍…
...the whole world would be gone.
整个世界现在就不复存在了
We can't run away from our responsibilities. This is who we are.
我们不能逃避责任,离开需要 我们保护的人,我们为此而生
- That's what I've been saying. - What about having a normal life?
- 我一直是这么说的 - 你不是想过普通人的生活?组织家庭
- A family? - Who says you have to be normal...
- 组成家庭 - 谁说一定要成为普通人…
...to have a family?
才可以建立家庭的
So are you up for another media-circus wedding? Fifth time's a charm.
那么你准备再办一个马戏媒体团婚礼 第五次,也算个吉利数了
No.
不
I got a better idea.
我有个更好的主意
Dearly beloved, we are gathered here today to join Reed Richards...
亲爱的朋友们,我们今天聚集于此 庆贺里德·理查斯…
...and Sue Storm together in holy...
和苏·史东的…神圣的
...matrimony.
婚姻
- What is it? - Venice is sinking into the Adriatic.
- 怎么了? - 威尼斯快要沉入了亚德里亚那海了
Oh, boy. That's a biggie.
哦,伙计们,那可是大事件
Could we just skip to the end?
我们能不能跳到最后?
- Yeah. The love these two share... - No, the very end.
- 好的,希望这对爱人分享… - 不是,是最最后…
Yeah, great. You have the rings?
哦,好极了,戒指带来了吗?
Oh, yeah.
噢,是的
I now pronounce you man and wife, and you may kiss the bride.
我现在宣布你们正式成为夫妇 你可以亲吻新娘了
- Okay. We should get out of here. - Yeah.
- 好吧,我们该走了 - 嗯
- Gotta go, hon. - Okay.
- 要走了,亲爱的 - 好的
I have to throw the bouquet.
我还要抛鲜花呢
Ready?
准备好了吗?
Heads up, Johnny.
抬头看,强尼
Sorry.
对不起
Reflex.
条件反射